hello my name is green and welcome back
to another hermitcraft video i am of
course
doing the never-ending mining of getting
more and more concrete this base
requires so much white concrete that i
think i've got through
about seven maybe more of these like
this was full this was full and now it's
empty the base just requires so much
work now i have done a fair few things
since the last episode one of which is
this automated sugarcane farm although
it's like the least productive thing
ever i don't know whether sugarcane just
grows really slowly if i've done
something wrong i really don't know but
it doesn't produce very much very often
i'm pretty sure i did this right it's a
very basic farm
but you know it doesn't matter too much
i need a lot of paper because i've been
working on my matrix room down there i
severely underestimated how much leather
how many sticks and maps i would need
which means of course a compass for
every single one which means four iron i
have used all of my iron it's not gone
well but i'm happy to say that it is
pretty much done in there there's just a
little bit more to cover up so this is
where the secret room is i think i might
cover this up with a piston so that this
goes this this retracts or something i'm
not entirely sure there needs to be some
sort of mechanism for sure
and then oh
boy
this is
amazing
it's so crazy now in order to make an
exit i had to
make a little corner but i've kind of
lost it
if if i walk around i'll find it i
promise
ah there it is
so you see there's this line now i can't
get rid of this
here i cannot get rid of this because
this is the side of the item frame i
have a couple of ideas to try out to
make this go away but as you can see if
you're here it completely vanishes but
if you walk forward enough then you get
some perspective the only way to really
know where you are is to throw a few
items around so that you can see where
you are in relation to it and then you
can work out this room looks absolutely
huge but it's not the end of the room is
somewhere around here yeah it's right
there look you can see the edge of the
wall right there
so this room is so cool
i can't wait to finish it because all i
need to do now is get a few more maps to
cover up the last little bit and i also
found out that you can put item frames
on the inside of the water tunnel so
apart from these fence gates everything
should be completely white the other
option of course is to put this tunnel
just on the inside here
i'm gonna sort of play around with
trying to make it completely flush and
then there's a little exit out there as
well in other related news i have
actually finished the elevator that goes
all the way to the top of this build
however the pulse extender doesn't quite
work the way i would hope now obviously
mumbo made one specifically to the
height of it so i i understand fully how
this works all it does is it's timed
perfectly so that the bubbles will stop
once you get to a certain level and then
it switches back to the magma block
however i need to make this pulse
extender
well i need to i need help matching it
up to the level so if i show you what i
mean this one if i click this this is to
go all the way to the top
but this is an extremely long elevator
so it gets about here and then it stops
and then i go back down again
it's it's not ideal however all of the
observers and bits where the different
floors are are all complete so what i
thought i would do in the meantime is
actually just make these holes a bit
better so i can just fly up and through
and i thought about making these really
nice and circular
i prefer flying absolutely everywhere so
this might be more than just temporary
but
i don't know it's kind of cool with the
whole beacon running straight through
the middle having these little holes
here where you can fly through might be
really useful but at the moment i've got
an elevator that goes only up it's not
redstoned at all so this just goes
straight up so we're gonna do exactly
the same thing here so it should be easy
just to fly between them i actually
wonder whether this elevator's gonna get
used at all with the amount that i love
flying around on the elytra i don't even
know if it's gonna be used
but i'm still gonna make it anyway for
people visiting it's quite cool and it
makes the bass feel more connected so in
today's episode we're mainly going to be
doing a lot of planning and scheming and
that kind of thing because
sometimes i get a bit ahead of myself in
what i want to do oh this is excellent
so as long as i fly correctly
everything should be fine with this
so what i've got here is four maps and i
thought since we're doing a lot of
planning this episode we might as well
sort of see what this looks like from
the sky
so we've got one quarter of it here and
quite quite nicely it's it's a little
bit off-center but it's caught most of
it there if we go into the other
quarters and take the maps there
then we might be able to get a really
nice effect okay i've got all parts of
the map now
and we can see what this looks like if
we put it together
i feel like we're going to need a bigger
one eventually but since this layer is
just like where i'm working at the
moment this has not been really put to
good use in terms of space management
like i've just put all of my farms over
in a corner but let's see what this
looks like
bottom right
and then we go the oh that's the top
right
oh would you look at that now that looks
really really cool i'm not gonna lie
that does look swish it even looks
fairly symmetrical there might be a
couple of mistakes but it does look like
the circle is pretty spot on so what you
might be able to see is a bit of a
difference from last episode is there's
these little squares here and there's
even one out there well that's what i'm
going to show you right now look at that
so this is the current state of the base
my initial thought was that this here
looked so just rigid coming straight up
it doesn't have any sort of flow
so what i did was i made these equal
every single level is equal because
before they were like
sort of alternating and it didn't look
as i originally thought so i've just
made these level all across the board
and then i created these additional
pieces coming out of the water right
here but i think this has worked really
well it really looks like the whole
thing really edges into the ground and
it looks a bit more at home now this
isn't finished i don't know how i'm
going to decorate these towers they are
extremely bland at the moment i think
what i'm going to do for now is finish
working on this section up here before i
start touching any of the towers and
there's still a lot of building to be
done especially when it comes to like
all the underwater stuff that you don't
really see but it doesn't look right
without it yeah it's just it's just
time-consuming really
anyway we're already getting a bit
distracted so let's finish one thing at
a time shall we let's go and finish this
matrix room my idea for making this work
a bit better is to add some dark oak
fence gates here
oh ouch
they all popped off because then what we
can do is put some item frames here and
that would make the entire room
completely flush now
wait oh no i turned around too much and
now i don't know where the exit is
uh did i even open it
oh this isn't good okay uh
let's put put a load of these round
okay that's one corner
i can't find the exit
there we go there we go i found the exit
so you can walk straight through this
bit but you have to know that this is
here in order to get out but it also
means that i could put it on the other
side as well as long as the every single
part of this
is covered up this could be a real
challenge
oh
and you only pass through it for a
second so i could actually put this
water thing here i don't know why i
created this whole extra room this was
so much more extra work than it needed
to be
but that that here this little bit here
is just a pass through it's like a gate
i could even try and put these on here
and see what that does
do they they don't pop off
once they're on they're on even if
there's a fence gate there you can still
pop them on
so that kind of makes it less jarring
but it might just be a waste i'm not too
sure without this bit here i wouldn't
know what's up and what's down we need
to know exactly where the walls are in
here and the best way to do that is just
throw the trident at the wall maybe i
should have done the building before i
put the maps down so i'm going to create
our meeting room right here this is
where i'm going to have my meetings if
any hermits come to see me this is this
is my base where's the end here so i
want one chair maybe here
so one chair here and then an equal
space
i just realized that this is definitely
not an equal room
but it doesn't matter too much
as long as we know where these chairs
are i know where the exit is because i
can be sitting here
and then i can work out where it is
exactly and to complete the room
there we go
oh my goodness this is so bizarre oops
you might actually find that by accident
if you're just like looking around
so this is really strange so this is the
meeting room see i know there's a wall
there i think it's just my mind playing
tricks on me but i know there's a wall
directly here you can't tell at all so
this is it this is the meeting room it's
as simple as that so mumbo's gonna be
there once i get him in here i'm gonna
drop an invite to him actually we're
gonna have to go over to his base and
drop an invite because i haven't
actually told him that he needs to come
and do a meeting with me whoops
i feel like i'm having slight second
thoughts about this room yeah you fall
in but then like do we want the chairs
here is it yes to chairs or no to chairs
let me know in the comments what you
guys think yes to chairs because this
makes it seem like the me the meeting
room of infinity the infinity oh that's
quite a nice name isn't it infinity
meeting room
if there is no chairs i'm not gonna know
where the exit is at all which could be
really good fun i didn't make the hole
all the way to the top can i fly through
this
oh my goodness i did yes i love flying
it's like my favorite thing in minecraft
okay we're gonna head over to mumbo's
base i haven't actually looked at
mumbo's base in a really long time so i
wonder what he's been up to nothing
seems to have changed much here he did
remove the pixel art i've seen i haven't
visited him in a while because he's not
been on the server too much he's been
away looks like he's made a city along
here
this is really cool now obviously i see
like glimpses of this base every now and
again when i'm flying around but i
haven't gone and had a look for a really
long time
it looks like he's got
automatic farms for kelp what's going on
in here this this looks like lag city to
me
this just looks like lag central i
wonder what this one does look at all
this see this is what i need this is
what i need him for whatever is going on
in here this is what i need
he's got a portal a really tall portal
anyway where's the best place to leave
him a message where would he go or maybe
in his underwater base i don't really
know where he goes anymore
i feel like he's still going to afk here
in fact why don't we leave it where he
afk is a lot
what
um
this is got this has got to be the most
bizarre thing that i've ever seen
why are there so many zombies here
they really like his sugar cane all
right we'll leave that where it is
this is his little afk spot so this is
where we're gonna leave him the message
okay i've left him the message hopefully
this is cryptic enough and should
install some sort of mystery
so it says
meet me in the infinity room for a chat
and to make plans go to
45843-941 and walk forward one block
i'll be there
g
now hopefully he still uses this as his
afk spot but knowing mumbo there's a
very high chance that he could miss this
all together so just to cover my bases
we're gonna spam so many torches that he
cannot possibly miss it he must think
that he'll see that something has gone a
bit odd here because of all the torches
so hopefully he won't miss this at all
now you're probably wondering why i'm
even having this meeting with mumbo
jumbo we're not working on any projects
together and
yeah you'd be right but
i actually have a plan
for
a project together
but that is for next episode i will
discuss that
very topic with mumbo himself hopefully
in the next episode so the instructions
told him to go directly here to walk
forward one block and then he falls into
the infinity room and hopefully
i'll be timed just right so that i'll be
waiting for him right here and then we
can talk but i want to see your
reactions first to know if i want to
keep these chairs or not so that's a
really good plan i like that where it's
going so far
and then we need to create some sort of
redstone door here somehow i'm not
entirely sure i'll figure that out
now there's something else that i have
to address in this video because i've
seen a few comments that are
particularly angry about all of the
torches and now that i've brought
attention to it yeah i don't like them
either i didn't like them at all in the
first place i've actually managed to
completely phase them out when i see
that when i like look at my base i don't
see torches at all but now i'm looking
at it
yeah it's bad they're not even in line
which is yeah i think that's probably
what's triggering people the most but i
thought maybe if we just use a few
carpets and
sea lanterns we can do something i wish
we had a few more light sources you know
i'm not really sure how to put these
apart from each other
i i really don't know i mean i could
just do a few like
glass circles or something that might be
a really cool way to do this by covering
up the sea lanterns there's still like a
little bit of something to look at you
still have the carpet here but it does
mean that we could create some sort of
pattern if we really wanted to instead
of just having it completely uniform
maybe i could do a few like gaps so one
two and then maybe oh maybe three or
four
we just need to make sure that mobs
don't spawn in here because i still
cannot safely afk in this space at all a
zombie appears from somewhere i don't
know where somewhere and i always get
killed it's actually really really bad
i've done the easy bit of just making
the lines across i just need to figure
out the best way to do this i would
really like to avoid a grid pattern like
this it's just not gonna look too good
unless i did like maybe not circles but
um i'm really i'm really not sure
i think maybe the best thing to do would
be to leave this until i actually have
an idea of what i want to do
but it definitely needs a pattern i'm
just not entirely convinced i know what
that is yet
but at least i can remove some of these
torches
now the next project i'm going to be
working on
is going to be on this layer here
and it's such a secret that i'm actually
going to put up my first ever spoiler
wall because i don't want anyone to see
what's being built here it's really
really important
this is the secret that is going to be
the biggest game changer in hermitcraft
so far
i'm not even going to spoil this for you
guys you will not see what i'm going to
create behind this spoiler wall it's a
pretty half-hearted effort for the wall
but this is important that this doesn't
get spoiled and i'm not entirely sure
how long it's going to take me to build
this
but
i imagine it's going to take a little
while i might even be able to finish
this for next episode i honestly just
don't know
right that'll do for now i'm gonna
properly cover this up so that not only
can i not spoil it for you guys by
flying around
that no one else can spoil it either so
behind this wall
there is going to be something very very
special but i really don't want to spoil
it for you guys yet because making plans
is really fun but sometimes you've got
to have a little surprise as well
so speaking of plans here's what i'm
thinking so this is my base this is
where the map is on the middle here
and i was thinking that we're going to
use these towers for different things
that sugarcane farm is pretty dire if i
do say so myself
i was wondering what if each tower had
its own farm in it
this one could be the mob farm and
that's probably the one that i want to
make first i just need to brush up on a
few redstone skills
maybe ask for a redstone guy's help and
then they can have access to the farm i
don't know something like that
so one of these towers because it's so
tall could produce a lot of items for me
and this is just all wasted space like
if we look going up here look at all
this space i can remove that i can look
there's mobs in there already they're
just waiting each layer could be used to
utilize it this has been spawning mobs
for so long and it even goes up even
higher
look look at all that space it's
probably not like the most efficient way
to use this but my goodness could this
utilize be utilized really really well
and that would leave a huge amount of
space for all of this stuff
i love this i love how high it is so
this one here i'm thinking can be the
mob farm this one here i mean this is
the elevator i can even keep this
elevator here and we can just look at
the mob farm i'm thinking this one could
potentially be
farms so
like an automated imagine that in each
layer i can just put an automated
pumpkin farm an automated sugarcane that
goes all the way up and it just auto
harvests and falls straight down to the
bottom and this can be a collection
point or something along those lines
and then i was wondering
if it's possible
to make an automated
storage system in here
now making a storage system is probably
something that i
cannot do it's probably a bit beyond my
skill level fortunately there are loads
of hermits that will likely offer up
their redstone skills in the future and
as long as i have enough money to pay
them it might be something worth
investing in for me
but that's kind of the plan at the
moment and then of course there are
these little ones here these little
towers that were purely built for
aesthetic purposes
right here these could also be used for
something else as well because there's
plenty of space in those i was even
thinking about filling in this space but
there are two different things like
there are filling these towers with
things that are going to be useful
actual function and then there's the
parts of the build which are going to be
purely aesthetic so the things that just
look good for example decorating these
towers it's going to just cost me
resources and time but at the end of the
day it's just making my base look pretty
so i really need to get my act together
and work out where i'm going with this
the time of freestyling this base might
be over because
it's really starting to mean a lot to me
how great this thing looks
but anyway i think that might be the end
of today's episode i know it's been a
lot of planning and stuff but sometimes
you've got to plan in order to get
everything together for future episodes
so to sort of recap we finished off the
matrix room we've made it our infinity
room and we're hoping that mumbo jumbo
will see the message and meet with me
very very soon to discuss a few things
we've also been working on these towers
we've made the elevator and we've
started putting up a spoiler wall for my
very secret project that i don't know
when it'll be finished to be honest with
you depending on how
easy it is to make it could be finished
very very soon or it could take a few
more weeks but one thing's for sure i
don't want anyone spoiling it it's also
halloween coming up and i need a
halloween skin i don't know what i'm
going to do maybe i could do like a
pumpkin green i don't know i i i i'll
think of something but if you guys have
any ideas hit me up on twitter and i
would love to get a cool halloween skin
i also think for halloween
we should scare someone and there's no
one that gets more spooked than good
times with scar i've accidentally scared
scar about
10 times and all i was doing was just
like saying hello so i think if we
really tried
we could actually scare him quite a lot
anyway that's it from me i'm going to
continue building this spoiler wall and
i will see you very soon in the next
episode thank you very much for watching
and good
bye